# Harris Schneiderman

# Senior Web Developer

San Diego, CA 92103 (517) 449-6532 me@harris-schneiderman.com www.harris-schneiderman.com https://github.com/schne324

#### **PROFILE**

I am an innovative web developer with 7+ years of experience building powerful web applications. My passion lies in front-end development. I was recently published in Smashing Magazine and have presented at several industry conferences.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Deque Systems | Ann Arbor, MI** - Senior Web Application Developer February 2013 - PRESENT

- Technical lead of agile team working on modern web applications
- Lead developer on Cauldron, Deque's front-end framework and pattern library used to create a consistent look and feel across all applications
- Developer of Chrome, Firefox, and Safari browser extensions
- Responsible for coaching team on following agile best practices and choosing the best tech stack for our apps
- Responsible for interviewing/hiring developers and mentoring junior developers

#### Performance Peddler | Garden City, MI - Software Developer

October 2012 - PRESENT (freelance)

- Using node.js to automate business tasks such as large data manipulation / extraction and bulk listing uploads using various APIs
- Develop and design ecommerce ad templates for eBay and amazon

#### Soles In Touch Reflexology | East Lansing, MI - Web Developer

August 2013 - March 2016 (freelance)

- Develop and design official website
- Build online appointment scheduling application

### **EDUCATION**

#### Michigan State University | East Lansing, MI - BA

September 2008 - December 2012

Bachelor of Arts: Media Arts & Technology (concentration of *Games, Web and Interactive Media*)

## **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

- Javascript/Node.js
- HTML/Pug (Jade)
- CSS/Less/Stylus/SCSS/Sass
- React
- Redux
- Express/Koa
- Webpack/Browserify/Gulp/Grunt
- Ava/Tape/Mocha/Jest
- MySQL/PostgreSQL/MongoDB
- Python
- PHP
- Accessibility expert of WAI-ARIA and WCAG
- Screen reader testing: NVDA/Jaws/VoiceOver/Talk Back

#### **PUBLICATIONS & PRESENTATIONS**

- Smashing Magazine publication Enter The Dragon (Drop): Accessible List Reordering
- Speaker at CSUN 2017 Advanced ARIA
- Speaker at CodeMash 2018 Designers and Developers Working Together: Mass Hysteria!
- Speaker at CSUN 2018 A Nightmare on HTML Street: Building Accessible Complex Widgets